Play for the planet.
Pixels is a action, comedy, science fiction film directed by Chris Columbus.
Video game experts are recruited by the military to fight
1980s-era video game characters who've attacked New York.
Brenner, played by Adam Sandler.
Cooper, played by Kevin James.
Violet, played by Michelle Monaghan.
Eddie, played by Peter Dinklage.
Ludlow, played by Josh Gad.
Matty, played by Matt Lintz.
Pixels (marketed as Pixels: The Movie) is a 2015 science fiction action comedy film
directed by Chris Columbus, and written by Tim Herlihy and Tim Dowling.
Loosely adapted from the 2010 short film, it stars Adam Sandler, Kevin James,
Michelle Monaghan, Peter Dinklage, Josh Gad and Brian Cox.
In the film, an alien force misinterprets video feeds of classic arcade games as a declaration of war,
resulting in them attacking Earth with technological recreations of icons from the games.
The president of the United States promptly assembles a team of
former arcade champions to lead the planet's defense.
Development began in 2010, when Sandler obtained the rights to Patrick Jean's short film via his
Happy Madison Productions company and began developing the script with Herlihy.
In 2013, Columbus entered talks to direct the film, drawn to the nostalgic homage to 1980s arcade games such
as Pac-Man, Donkey Kong and Space Invaders, all of which were licensed for use in the film.
Filming took place in Toronto for three months, which
involved extensive night shoots and practical sets.
Post-production, led by Digital Domain and Sony Pictures Imageworks, focused on creating
voxelized 3D versions of arcade characters to integrate into the live-action scenes.
Pixels was released theatrically in the United States on
July 24, 2015, by Sony Pictures Releasing.
The film received negative reviews from critics, and grossed $245 million.
The film explores themes of new york city, london, england,
usa president, washington dc, usa, video game.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.